A Finding Aid to the Walter Pach Papers, 1857-1980, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Selections from Walter Pach's Library, 1880-1963; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 12 Linear feet Box 11-22
  - Selected Publications, 1880-1963; 10.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Camera Work (New York, Alfred Stieglitz), no. 32, 1910 October; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Cassou, Jean. Jacques Villon. Paris: Musée National d'Art Moderne, 1951 February 5-March 25; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Catalogue de photographies, d'art moderne, d'art ancien. Druet Photograph Collection. Paris: Librairie de France, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Chap-Book: Semi-Monthly (Chicago), 1895 August 15; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17)
      Includes a portrait of Stéphane Mallarmé by F. Vallotton.
    - Chassé, Charles. Gauguin et le groupe de Pont-Aven. Documents inédits. Paris: H. Floury, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Les chefs-d'oeuvre des peintres florentins. Vol. 4, Paolo Uccello, Domenico Veneziano, Masaccio et A. Del Castagno. Paris: A. Perche, Petite Collection d'Art, Gowans 41, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - City College Alumnus (Associate Alumni of the College of the City of New York, Inc.) 32, no. 2, 1936 February.; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 20)
      Includes article on the Walter Pach mural given to CCNY.
    - Clark, Eliot. History of the National Academy of Design, 1825-1953. New York: Columbia University Press, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Clarke, John Lee, Jr. David and Ingres, Paintings and Drawings. Springfield, Mass.: Springfield Museum of Fine Arts, 1939 November 20-December 17; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Coffin, Robert P. Tristram. Strange Holiness. New York: MacMillan Company, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Corrard, Pierre (? la mémoire de). Poésies. 16 original etchings by Jacques Villon. Paris: La Librairie J. Meynial, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Courthion, Pierre. Gino Severini. Arte Moderna Italiana 17, Series A, Pittori 13. Milan: Si Vende Presso La Libreria Ulrico Hoepli, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Cruikshank, George, illus. The Loving Ballad of Lord Bateman. Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1884; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Delacroix, Eugène. Études Esthétiques. Les Editions, G. Cres & Co., 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Delacroix, Eugène. Journal de Eugène Delacroix. Vol. 2, 1853-1856. Edited by André Joubin. Paris: Librairie Plon, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Delacroix, Eugène. Journal de Eugène Delacroix. Vol. 3, 1857-1863. Edited by André Joubin. Paris: Librairie Plon, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Delacroix, Eugène. Lettres de Eugène Delacroix, First Book (1804-1847). Edited by Philippe Burty. Paris: G. Charpentier, 1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Delacroix, Eugène. Lettres de Eugène Delacroix, Second Book (1848-1863). Edited by Philippe Burty. Paris: G. Charpentier, 1880; Archival Resource Key; 2 Copies (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Delacroix, Eugène. Oeuvres littéraires Vol. 1, Etudes esthétiques. Paris: Bibliothèque Dionysienne, Les Editions G. Crès & Cie, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Detroit Institute of Arts. Origins of Modern Sculpture. Detroit, 1946 January 22-March 3; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - De Zayas, Marius, and Paul B. Haviland. A Study of the Modern Evolution of Plastic Expression. New York: "291,", 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Diehl, Charles. Manuel d'art byzantin. Paris: Librairie Alphonse Picard et Fils, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Dufy, Raoul. Les Alliés, Petit panorama des uniformes Vol. 1. [Paris], circa 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Includes a woodcut enclosed with booklet
    - L'Elan (Paris), no. 1-no. 9, 1915-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Elia, Olga. Pitture murali e mosaici nel Museo Nazionale di Napoli. Rome: La Libreria Dello Stato, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Escholier, Raymond. Gros: Ses amis et ses Elèves. Illustrated. Paris: Librairie Floury, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Farwell, Beatrice. The Metropolitan Museum of Art Miniatures, Eugène Delacroix, 1798-1863. New York: Distributed by Book-of-the-Month Club, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Faure, Elie. Histoire de l'art: L'art antique. Paris: H. Floury, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Faure, Elie. Histoire de l'art: L'art antique. Paris: Les Editions G. Crès & Cie, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Faure, Elie. Histoire de l'art: L'art médiéval. Paris: H. Floury, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Faure, Elie. Histoire de l'art: L'art médiéval and Histoire de l'art: L'art moderne. Paris: Les Editions G. Crès & Cie, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Faure, Elie. Histoire de l'art: L'art renaissant. Paris: H. Floury, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Faure, Elie. Histoire de l'art: L'esprit des formes. Paris: Les Editions G. Crès & Cie, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Faure, Elie. Méditations catastrophiques. Paris: Jean Flory, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Faure, Elie. Paul Gauguin. New York: Association of American Painters and Sculptors, Inc., 1913.; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14)
      Faure's name is crossed out, and Walter Pach has changed it to Bela Lasar.
    - Faure, Elie. Soutine. Paris: Les Editions G. Crès et Cie, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Faure, Jean-Pierre. Alger capitale. Paris: Bibliothèque du Hérisson, Société Française d'Editions Littéraires et Techniques, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Flaubert, Gustave. Trois contes. Paris: Bibliothèque-Charpentier, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Flexner, James Thomas. The Pocket History of American Painting. New York: Pocket Books, Inc., by arrangement with Houghton Mifflin Company, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Focillon, Henri. The Life of Forms in Art. New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Press, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Frénaud, André. Les mystères de Paris. Preface by Paul Eluard and signed etching by Jacques Villon. Paris: Editions du Seuil, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Galerie Craven. Octobre, Hommage à Picabia. Paris, 1953 October 1-29; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Galerie La Boëtie. Salon de "La Section d'Or". Preface by René Blum. Paris, 1912 October 10-30; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Galeries Georges Petit. Exposition Ingres Paris, 1911 April 26-May 14; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Galleries M. Knoedler and Company, Inc. El Greco: Loan Exhibition for the Benefit of the Greek War Relief Association. New York, 1941 January 17-February 15; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Pach was a lender to the exhibition.
    - Gallery Der Sturm. Die Futuristen Berlin, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Gauguin, Paul. Noa-Noa. Translated by Walt Kuhn. New York: Association of American Painters and Sculptors, Inc., 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Gertrude, Gertrude S. Lemons and Poppies. New York: Thomas Seltzer, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Gleizes, Albert. Du cubisme et des moyens de le comprendre. Paris: Editions "La Cible,", 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Gleizes, Albert. Peinture et perspective descriptive. Sablons, France: Editions Moly-Sabata, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Gowans, Adam L., comp. Lyric Masterpieces by Living Authors. London and Glasgow: Gowans and Gray, Ltd., 1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - La Grande Revue (Paris) 12, no. 24, 1908 December 25; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 15)
      Includes "Notes d'un peintre, by Henri Matisse.
    - Grappe, Georges. Edgar Degas. Berlin: Erschienen bei der Verlagsanstalt fur Litteratur und Kunst, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Gsell, Paul. Millet. Paris: Les Editions Rieder, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Henry, Daniel. Der Weg zum Kubismus. Munich: Delphin-Verlag, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Hokusai, Manga, undated.; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Two books of studies, text in Japanese.
    - Hôtel Drouot. Art océanien, Art africain, Art américain, Asie et Malaisie. Paris, Sale 11, 1929 November 7-9; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Hôtel Drouot. Collection Maurice Gangnat. Catalog of works by Renoir, Cézanne, and Vuillard. Paris, Sales 9, 10, and 11, 1925 June 24-25; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Hôtel Drouot. Estampes, dessins, aquarelles: Anciens et modernes. Paris, Sale 9, 1931 April 22; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Hôtel Drouot. Estampes et dessins: Livres sur les arts. Paris, Sale 12, 1929 November 23; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Hôtel Drouot. Tableaux, aquarelles, dessins. Paris, Sale 1, 1921 May 30; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Hôtel Drouot. Tableaux et dessins par J.-A.-D. Ingres: Collection de Monsieur Henry Lapauze. Paris, Sales 7 and 8, 1929 June 21; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Hôtel Drouot. Tableaux, pastels, aquarelles, dessins, eaux-fortes & lithographies. Paris, Sale 8, 1929 December 21; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Institute of Contemporary Art. Jacques Villon, Lyonel Feininger. Contributions by Jacques Villon, George Heard Hamilton, Thomas B. Hess, and Frederick S. Wight. Boston, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Jacques Seligmann & Co, Inc. Twenty Years in the Evolution of Picasso, 1903-1923. New York, 1937 November 1-20; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Janis, Harriet, and Sidney Janis. Picasso, The Recent Years, 1939-1946. New York: Doubleday & Company, Inc., Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - John Quinn, 1870-1925: Collection of Paintings, Water Colors, Drawings & Sculpture. Huntington, N.Y.: Pidgeon Hill Press, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Joubin, André. Journal de Eugène Delacroix. Vol. 1, 1822-1852. Paris: Librairie Plon, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Keller, Jean, and Raymond Duchamp-Villon. Les sémaphores: Bouffonnerie sensorielle en un acte. Châlons-sur-Marne, France: Imprimerie-Librairie de L'Union Républicaine, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Klossowski, Erich. Katalog einer Auswahl Französischer Meister. Munich: Kunstsalon W. Zimmermann, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Kruse, Alexander, and Alfred Kreymborg. Two New Yorkers. Edited by Stanley Burnshaw. New York and Boston: Bruce Humphries, Inc., 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Lassaigne, Jacques, and Jacques Villon. Jacques Villon: Peintres et sculpteurs d'aujourd'hui. Paris: Collection "Signe," Editions de Beaune, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Lebel, Robert. Léonard de Vinci: Ou la fin de l'humilité. Paris: Presses du Livre Français, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Le Roy, Jean. Le Cavalier de Frise: Poèmes inédits de Jean Le Roy. Preface by Jean Cocteau. Paris: François Bernouard, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Le Roy, Jean. Le prisonnier des mondes: Poèmes. Paris and Rome: Société d'Editions Mansi & Cie, dated by Pach as, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Lichtenstein, Isaac, and Abraham Walkowitz. Jewish Artists. New York: Machmadim Art Editions, Inc., 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Low, Theodore L. The Museum as a Social Instrument. New York: Metropolitan Museum of Art, for the American Association of Museums, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Marin, John. Letters of John Marin. Edited by Herbert J. Seligmann. New York: Privately Printed for An American Place, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Maugard, Adolfo Best. Manuales y tratados metodo de dibujo, Tradicion, resurgimiento y evolucion del arte mexicano. Mexico City: Departamento Editorial de la Secretariad Educacion, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Meier-Graefe, Julius. Courbet. Munich: R. Piper & Co. Verlag, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Meier-Graefe, Julius. Eugène Delacroix: Beiträge zu einer Analyse. Munich: R. Piper & Co. Verlag, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Meier-Graefe, Julius. Impressionisten: Guys, Manet, Van Gogh, Pissarro, Cézanne. Munich and Leipzig: R. Piper & Co. Verlag, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Meier-Graefe, Julius. Pyramide und Tempel. Berlin: Ernst Rowohlt Verlag, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Meier-Graefe, Julius. Renoir Leipzig: Klinkhardt & Biermann Verlag, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Meier-Graefe, Julius. Der Vater. Berlin: S. Fischer Verlag, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Mercure de France (Paris) 18, vol. 69, no. 247, 1907 October 1; Archival Resource Key; 2 Copies Two copies, one partial (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Mercure de France(Paris) 18, vol. 70, no. 248, 1907 October 16; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Montross Gallery. Henri Matisse Exhibition. New York, 1915 January 20-February 27; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Mumford, Lewis. Man as Interpreter. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Mumford, Lewis. Technics and Civilization. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Museum of Modern Art. Art in Our Time. Exhibition to celebrate the tenth anniversary of the Museum and the opening of its new building. New York. Pach lent a Duchamp painting., 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Palais des Beaux-Arts. Collection de Monsieur L.L.: Tableaux modernes, Faïences de Delft et de Rhodes, Objets d'art. Brussels, 1931 December 22-23; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Auction/Sales Catalogue. New York, October 17. Dates written in:, 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Auction/Sales Catalogue. New York:, 1942 January 8; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Classical and Medieval Stone Sculptures, Joseph Brummer Collection, Part III (Final). New York, 1949 June 8-9; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Modern French and American Paintings from the Walter Pach, Mrs. Jacob H. Rand, and Other Collections. New York, 1949 January 6; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Part Two of the Notable Art Collection... Joseph Brummer. New York, 1949 May 11-14; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Perkins, Christopher. On Museums: An Essay. Saint-Tropez, France: Au Paysage du Midi, 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Popular Stories Collected by the Brothers Grimm. London: Oxford University Press, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Portraits d'hier, Studies of the Life, Works, and Influence of the Late Great Figures (Grands Morts) of Our Time 2, no. 28, 1910, May; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Includes "Paul Cézanne," by Elie Faure.
    - Raynal, Maurice. Jacques Lipchitz. Paris: Editions Jeanne Bucher, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Reality: A Journal of Artists' Opinions (New York) 1, no. 1, 1953 Spring; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Rewald, John. Georges Seurat. New York: Wittenborn and Company, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Rewald, John, Dore Ashton, Harold Joachim, and Odilon Redon. Odilon Redon/Gustave Moreau/Rodolphe Bresdin. New York: Museum of Modern Art in collaboration with the Art Institute of Chicago, distributed by Doubleday & Co., Inc., 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Rich, Daniel Catton. The Challenge of Art in the Americas: An Address Given to the Graduating Classes School of the Art Institute. Chicago, 1944 June 9; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Richter, J.P. Lectures on the National Gallery. London, New York, and Bombay: Longmans, Green, and Co., 1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff. Abstract Painting and Sculpture in America. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1951.; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 20)
      Walter Pach's painting was included in exhibition.
    - Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff. "The Evolution of Ingres' Portrait of the Comtesse d'Haussonville." Art Bulletin (College Art Association of America) 22, no. 3, Reprint, 1940 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Robin, Maurice. "Eugène Delacroix," Portraits d'Hier, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Sérusier, Paul. ABC de la peinture, and ABC de la peinture: Correspondance. Paris: Henri Floury, La Douce France, 1921; Archival Resource Key; 2 Copies (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Seven Famous Greek Plays. Introduction by Whitney J. Oates and Eugene O'Neill, Jr. New York: Random House, Inc., Modern Library College Editions, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Severini, Gino. Ragionamenti sulle arti figurative. Milan: Editore Ulrico Hoepli, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - S.F. Bay Exposition Co. Art. Official Catalog, Golden Gate International Exposition, Palace of Fine Arts. San Francisco, 1940.; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Sloan, John, and Oliver LaFarge. Introduction to American Indian Art. New York: Exposition of Indian Tribal Arts, Inc., 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Smith College Museum of Art, Tryon Art Gallery. Géricault. Northampton, Mass., 1929 April 4-25; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Société des artistes indépendants. Catalog of the 24th Exposition. Paris, 1908 March 20-May 2; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Society of Independent Artists, Inc. The Bylaws, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Society of Independent Artists, Inc. The 20th Annual Anniversary Exhibition. New York, 1936 April 24-May 17.; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Walter and Magda Pach were directors and lenders.
    - Stein, Leo. The A-B-C of Aesthetics. New York: Boni & Liveright, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Stein, Leo. Journey into the Self: Being the Letters, Papers & Journals of Leo Stein. Edited by Edmund Fuller. Introduction by Van Wyck Brooks. New York: Crown Publishers, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Taylor, Francis Henry. Babel's Tower: The Dilemma of the Modern Museum. New York: Columbia University Press, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Transition: A Quarterly Review (New York), no. 26, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Tzara, Tristan. La Première aventure céleste de Mr. Antipyrine. With color woodcuts by Marcel Janco. Zurich: Collection Dada, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico. Anales del Instituto de Investigaciones Esteticas. Indices to Vol. 2, nos. 5,6,7, and 8. Mexico City, 1942.; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Lists Walter Pach's article "Arte mexicano en Nueva York," no. 6, p. 5.
    - University Museum Bulletin (University Museum, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia) 16, no. 3, 1952 February.; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 14)
      Includes "Fourteen Eyes in a Museum Storeroom.".
    - Valentiner, William R. "The Museum of Tomorrow." In New Architecture and City Planning, edited by Paul Zucker. New York: Philosophical Library, Reprint, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. The Songs We Sing. New York: Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Variétés critiques. Paris: Les Editions G. Crès & Cie, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Venturi, Adolfo. Luca Signorelli. Firenze: Presso Giorgio & Piero Alinari, 1921-1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - La Vie (Paris) no. 41, 1912 November 30; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - La Vie (Paris) no. 42, 1912 December 7; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - La Vie (Paris) no. 43, 1912 December 14; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - La Vie des Lettres et des Arts (Paris), 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 22)
      Includes "La peinture et ses lois: Ce qui devait sortir du cubisme," by Albert Gleizes.
    - View: Max Ernst Number (New York), 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - View, The Modern Magazine: Marcel Duchamp Number (New York) 5, no. 1, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Le père Ubu à l'aviation. Paris: Editions Georges Crès et Cie, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Le père Ubu à l'hôpital. Paris: Editions Georges Crès et Cie, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Le père Ubu au pays des Soviets. Paris: Librairie Stock, Delamain, Boutelleau et Cie, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Les réincarnations du père Ubu. Paris: Le Divan, 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. A Demonstration of Objective, Abstract, and Non-Objective Art. Girard, Kans.: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. Isadora Duncan in Her Dances. Girard, Kans.: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Wechsler, Herman J., ed. The Pocket Book of Old Masters. New York: Pocket Books, Inc., 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Wexley, John. The Last Mile. A play in three acts, with Preface by Lewis E. Lawes, Warden of Sing Sing Prison. New York and Los Angeles: Samuel French, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art. Abstract Painting in America. Introduction by Stuart Davis. New York, 1935 February 12-March 22; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art. Between Two Wars: Prints by American Artists, 1914-1941. New York, 1942 March 3-31.; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 34)
      Walter Pach's work was in the exhibition.
    - Whitney Museum of American Art. The Decade of the Armory Show, 1910-1920. New York, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 35)